export const fullQuizData = [
  {
    "question": "The level of complexity of a system should NOT influence the methodology used to reverse engineer it",
    "options": [
      "False",
      "True"
    ],
    "correct": "False"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is incorrect about Oligonucleotide Design in a microarray?",
    "options": [
      "DNA microarrays are generated by fixing oligonucleotides onto a solid support",
      "The oligonucleotides don’t react with cDNA samples",
      "The oligonucleotide array slide represents thousands of preselected genes from an organism",
      "The length of oligonucleotides is typically in the range of twenty-five to seventy bases long"
    ],
    "correct": "The oligonucleotides don’t react with cDNA samples"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is incorrect about a microarray?",
    "options": [
      "Array of immobilized DNA oligomers cannot be cDNAs",
      "slide attached with a high-density array of immobilized DNA oligomers representing the entire genome",
      "It is the most commonly used global gene expression profiling method",
      "Each oligomer is spotted on the slide and serves as probe for binding to a unique complementary cDNA"
    ],
    "correct": "Array of immobilized DNA oligomers cannot be cDNAs"
  },
  {
    "question": "A complete diagnostic process automatization is not generally feasible at present",
    "options": [
      "False",
      "True"
    ],
    "correct": "True"
  },
  {
    "question": "In eukaryotes, gene expression is not regulated by a protein complex formed between transcription factors and RNA polymerase",
    "options": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct": "False"
  },
  {
    "question": "Marker 3D position cannot be precisely reconstructed using triangulation",
    "options": [
      "False",
      "True"
    ],
    "correct": "False"
  },
  {
    "question": "The length of the reads is one of the biggest obstacles in sequencing genomes",
    "options": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct": "True"
  },
  {
    "question": "The shotgun approach ______ sequences clones from ______ of cloned DNA.",
    "options": [
      "specifically, one end",
      "randomly, one end",
      "specifically, both ends",
      "randomly, both ends"
    ],
    "correct": "randomly, both ends"
  },
  {
    "question": "Automated sleep stage classification",
    "options": [
      "Is difficult because the data set is very imbalanced",
      "achieves high performance especially for the N1 stage detection",
      "is commonly used in the clinical practice, and manual screening is now obsolete",
      "is not very useful because manual screening is little time consuming"
    ],
    "correct": "Is difficult because the data set is very imbalanced"
  },
  {
    "question": "The SANGER method can be used to discover the amminoacid sequence of a protein:",
    "options": [
      "False",
      "True"
    ],
    "correct": "False"
  },
  {
    "question": "The shape of a protein is encoded into its amminoacid sequence",
    "options": [
      "False",
      "True"
    ],
    "correct": "True"
  },
  {
    "question": "Despite the multiple coverage, sometimes certain genomic regions remain unsequenced, mainly owing to cloning difficulties",
    "options": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct": "True"
  },
  {
    "question": "Base pairing, in RNA, is A-G and U-C",
    "options": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct": "False"
  },
  {
    "question": "Motor complications in Parkinson's disease include:",
    "options": [
      "Freezing of gait, tremor",
      "Bradykinesia, postural instability",
      "Dyskinesia, freezing of gait",
      "OFF periods, bradykinesia"
    ],
    "correct": "Dyskinesia, freezing of gait"
  },
  {
    "question": "Machine Learning (vs Deep learning) requires more data but reduces user dependency, requires much computational power, less interpretable",
    "options": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct": "False"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is untrue about distance based methods",
    "options": [
      "pairwise distance scores in matrix, a phylogenetic tree can be constructed for all the taxa involved",
      "computed evo distances can be used to construct a matrix of distances between all pairs of taxa",
      "clustering algos compute tree based on distance matrix starting from the most similar sequence pairs",
      "Clustering is the only method among the algorithms for the distance-based tree-building method"
    ],
    "correct": "Clustering is the only method among the algorithms for the distance-based tree-building method"
  },
  {
    "question": "Voice can represent an early marker of neurodegeneration",
    "options": [
      "False",
      "True"
    ],
    "correct": "True"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is incorrect about Hierarchical Clustering?",
    "options": [
      "The tree-branching pattern illustrates a higher degree of relationship between related gene groups",
      "tree leaves, similar gene expression profiles are placed closely together than dissimilar gene expr",
      "It is not similar to the distance phylogenetic tree-building method",
      "It produces a treelike structure that represents a hierarchy or relative relatedness of data groups"
    ],
    "correct": "It is not similar to the distance phylogenetic tree-building method"
  },
  {
    "question": "Sometimes, it is also possible that two sequences have derived from a common ancestor, but may have diverged to such an extent that the common ancestral relationships are not recognizable at the sequence level.",
    "options": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct": "True"
  },
  {
    "question": "The 'central dogma' says that a mRNA molecule can be translated back to DNA",
    "options": [
      "False",
      "True"
    ],
    "correct": "False"
  },
  {
    "question": "Final Results: Risposta Corretta",
    "options": [],
    "correct": ""
  },
  {
    "question": "The shotgun approach does not require knowledge of physical mapping of the clone fragments, but rather a robust computer assembly program to join pieces of random fragments into a single, whole-genome sequence",
    "options": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct": "True"
  },
  {
    "question": "For many eukaryotic proteins, newly synthesized protein precursors have to be transported to specific membrane-bound compartments and be proteolytically processed to become functional",
    "options": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct": "True"
  },
  {
    "question": "The degree of sequence variation in the alignment reveals evolutionary relatedness of different sequences, whereas the conservation between sequences reflects the changes that have occurred during evolution in the form of subs, insertions, and deletions",
    "options": [
      "False",
      "True"
    ],
    "correct": "False"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a form of RNA?",
    "options": [
      "rRNA",
      "qRNA",
      "tRNA",
      "mRNA"
    ],
    "correct": "qRNA"
  },
  {
    "question": "In DNA sequencing, the fluorescent traces of the DNA sequences are read by a computer program that assigns bases for each peak in a chromatogram.",
    "options": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct": "True"
  },
  {
    "question": "Hand tracking poses is less challenging than body tracking",
    "options": [
      "False",
      "True"
    ],
    "correct": "False"
  },
  {
    "question": "If the two sequences share significant similarity, it is extremely ______ that the extensive similarity between the two sequences has been acquired randomly, meaning that the two sequences must have derived from a common evolutionary origin.",
    "options": [
      "relevant",
      "possible",
      "unlikely",
      "likely"
    ],
    "correct": "unlikely"
  },
  {
    "question": "In Protein – Protein Interactions the physical contacts between domains are crucial for the functioning of the cellular machinery.",
    "options": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct": "True"
  },
  {
    "question": "During Data Cleaning, outliers should be always removed from datasets",
    "options": [
      "False",
      "True"
    ],
    "correct": "False"
  },
  {
    "question": "Reverse engineering using a top-down approach",
    "options": [
      "is best for linear systems",
      "Allows to identify relationships between the parts of the system",
      "is a sequencing technique",
      "is the methodology used by most Life Science researchers"
    ],
    "correct": "is a sequencing technique"
  },
  {
    "question": "Reverse engineering, is the processes of extracting knowledge from something and reproducing it based on the extracted information",
    "options": [
      "False",
      "True"
    ],
    "correct": "True"
  },
  {
    "question": "TATA box is often used as an indicator of the presence of a promoter",
    "options": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct": "True"
  },
  {
    "question": "Dissociated sleep means:",
    "options": [
      "excessive skeletal muscle atonia during REM stage",
      "lack of smooth muscle atonia during REM stage",
      "lack of skeletal muscle atonia during REM stage",
      "lack of eye muscle atonia during REM stage"
    ],
    "correct": "lack of skeletal muscle atonia during REM stage"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not a base of RNA?",
    "options": [
      "Cytosine (C)",
      "Adenine (A)",
      "Guanine (G)",
      "Thymine (T)"
    ],
    "correct": "Thymine (T)"
  },
  {
    "question": "Phylogenetic relationship can be shown by",
    "options": [
      "Gene Bank",
      "Data retrieving tool",
      "Dendrogram",
      "Data search tool"
    ],
    "correct": "Dendrogram"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is an incorrect statement about the terminologies related to protein sorting?",
    "options": [
      "Many proteins exhibit functions only after being transported to certain compartments of the cell",
      "Subcellular localization is an integral part of protein functionality",
      "All the proteins exhibit functions after being transported to certain compartments of the cell",
      "Protein sorting is also known as protein targeting"
    ],
    "correct": "All the proteins exhibit functions after being transported to certain compartments of the cell"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is untrue regarding Prediction with Neural Networks?",
    "options": [
      "A neural network is trained by a single sequence",
      "A neural network is trained by a sequence profile derived from the multiple sequence alignment",
      "When multiple sequence alignments and neural networks are combined, the result is improved accuracy",
      "...it applies the rules learned in training to recognize particular structural patterns"
    ],
    "correct": "A neural network is trained by a single sequence"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of these sentences on cross-individual transfer learning is correct?",
    "options": [
      "It is not feasible at all, a merely abstract concept",
      "It impairs the performance of most algorithms",
      "It means to train the network on Patient 1 and partially reuse on Patient 2",
      "It means to train the network on Patient 1 and totally reuse on Patient 2"
    ],
    "correct": "It means to train the network on Patient 1 and partially reuse on Patient 2"
  },
  {
    "question": "A good estimation metric for balanced dataset is accuracy",
    "options": [
      "False",
      "True"
    ],
    "correct": "True"
  },
  {
    "question": "In microarray data-If replicated datasets are available, statistical tests such as t-test and ANOVA can be performed to test the null hypothesis that a given data point is not significantly different from the mean of the data distribution.",
    "options": [
      "False",
      "True"
    ],
    "correct": "True"
  },
  {
    "question": "Structures are not much important when it comes to the study of the functions",
    "options": [
      "False",
      "True"
    ],
    "correct": "False"
  },
  {
    "question": "Unlike DNA, which is mainly double stranded, RNA is single stranded, although an RNA molecule can self-hybridize at certain regions to form partial double-stranded structures",
    "options": [
      "False",
      "True"
    ],
    "correct": "True"
  },
  {
    "question": "The cost of Data Cleaning is negligible when compared to the cost of running lab experiments",
    "options": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct": "False"
  },
  {
    "question": "Petri nets",
    "options": [
      "have been defined to represent biological data",
      "have been created in the late 90'",
      "do not allow to model stochasticity",
      "can simulate the dynamics of a system"
    ],
    "correct": "can simulate the dynamics of a system"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is incorrect regarding pairwise sequence alignment?",
    "options": [
      "It's an important first step toward structural and functional analysis of newly determined sequences",
      "The most fundamental process in this type of comparison is sequence alignment",
      "...patterns and establishing residue-residue correspondence among related sequences",
      "It is the process of aligning multiple sequences"
    ],
    "correct": "It is the process of aligning multiple sequences"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is untrue regarding Prediction with Neural Networks?",
    "options": [
      "Between input and output are many connected hidden layers",
      "Between the connected hidden layers ML takes place to adjust the maths weights of connections",
      "It has to be first trained by sequences with known structures",
      "It doesn't have to be first trained by sequences with known structures"
    ],
    "correct": "It doesn't have to be first trained by sequences with known structures"
  },
  {
    "question": "The ______ refers to a structure with two ends of a single-stranded region (loop) connecting a base-paired region (stem).",
    "options": [
      "bulge loop",
      "hairpin loop",
      "interior loop",
      "helical junctions"
    ],
    "correct": "hairpin loop"
  },
  {
    "question": "An Attractor",
    "options": [
      "is a stable state of a boolean network",
      "is an unstable state in a complex system",
      "is the process that makes two cells move toward each others",
      "is a stable state in a protein-to-protein interaction network"
    ],
    "correct": "is a stable state of a boolean network"
  },
  {
    "question": "When the two domains are located in two different proteins, to preserve the same functionality, their close proximity and interaction have to be conserved as well",
    "options": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct": "True"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is incorrect about k-Means Clustering",
    "options": [
      "It classifies data through a single step partition",
      "In this method, data are partitioned into k-clusters, which are prespecified at the outset",
      "k-means clustering produces a dendrogram",
      "It is a divisive approach"
    ],
    "correct": "k-means clustering produces a dendrogram"
  },
  {
    "question": "The REM sleep is characterized by frequent limb movements",
    "options": [
      "False",
      "True"
    ],
    "correct": "False"
  },
  {
    "question": "The promoter sequence may determine the expression of one gene or a number of linked genes downstream",
    "options": [
      "False",
      "True"
    ],
    "correct": "True"
  },
  {
    "question": "In motion capture systems, markers can be either passive or active",
    "options": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct": "True"
  },
  {
    "question": "In a linear system some functionalities emerge from the interaction of its parts",
    "options": [
      "False",
      "True"
    ],
    "correct": "False"
  },
  {
    "question": "The ‘central dogma’ says that a protein can be translated back to mRNA",
    "options": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct": "False"
  },
  {
    "question": "Machine Learning algorithms are always extremely efficient when dealing with Biological data",
    "options": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct": "False"
  },
  {
    "question": "Deep Learning (vs Machine learning) requires much more data but improves generalization capability, requires much computational power, less interpretable",
    "options": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct": "True"
  },
  {
    "question": "The specific DNA sequences to which the transcription factors bind are referred to as",
    "options": [
      "regulatory elements",
      "blocking factors",
      "transcription factors",
      "replication elements"
    ],
    "correct": "regulatory elements"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which of the following is not the objective to perform sequence comparison?",
    "options": [
      "To observe patterns of conservation",
      "To find the common motifs present in both sequences",
      "To study evolutionary relationships",
      "To study the physical properties of molecules"
    ],
    "correct": "To study the physical properties of molecules"
  },
  {
    "question": "In addition to RNA polymerase, there are also a number of DNA-binding proteins that facilitate the process of transcription",
    "options": [
      "False",
      "True"
    ],
    "correct": "True"
  },
  {
    "question": "A good estimation metric for balanced dataset is F-score",
    "options": [
      "False",
      "True"
    ],
    "correct": "True"
  },
  {
    "question": "Chronic patients should be always treated at home",
    "options": [
      "False",
      "True"
    ],
    "correct": "True"
  },
  {
    "question": "The gene is a union of genomic sequences encoding a coherent set of potentially overlapping functional products",
    "options": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct": "True"
  },
  {
    "question": "Voice can support clinicians in the objective assessment of many neurodegenerative condition",
    "options": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct": "True"
  },
  {
    "question": "Many deep learning solutions are possible for 2D and 3D body tracking/pose estimation",
    "options": [
      "True",
      "False"
    ],
    "correct": "True"
  },
  {
    "question": "Deep learning in sleep disorder classification:",
    "options": [
      "is always to be preferred to machine learning methods",
      "is infeasible because polysomnographic data are scarce",
      "lacks interpretability, which is a key issue in the clinical practice",
      "is validated by numerous controlled trials"
    ],
    "correct": "lacks interpretability, which is a key issue in the clinical practice"
  },
  {
    "question": "Threshold processing of inertial data for fall prevention:",
    "options": [
      "is feasible and simple but yields many false negatives",
      "always outperforms statistical methods",
      "is feasible and simple but yields many false positives",
      "is infeasible"
    ],
    "correct": "is feasible and simple but yields many false positives"
  }
];